Guide to the Asa Fish Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Asa Fish papers
1810-1855
MS 963
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.5
Letters from family, friends, and business associates of Asa Fish chiefly relating to ocean going trade, whaling, and sealing around the Cape of Good Hope and marine insurance. Also some material on politics in Connecticut.
Fish, Asa, 1790-1861
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased, 1956.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The Asa Fish Papers consist of letters, printed notices, and commercial papers that Fish received from relatives, friends, and associates in business and public life. The letters touch on all his interests but are mainly concerned with ocean-going trade (mainly between American ports), marine insurance, whaling and sealing around the Cape of Good Hope, banking in New London County, minor business of the probate court, and Republican-Whig politics in Connecticut. The coverage is fragmentary.
Biographical / Historical
Asa Fish was born in Stonington, Connecticut, on July 17, 1790. He was the son of Sands Fish and Bridget Gallup. He was a merchant, insurance agent, bank and railroad director, selectman, probate judge, state legislator, and political and civic leader of Stonington. He was married to Prudence Brown Dean on September 30, 1818. Fish died in Mystic, Connecticut, on April 20, 1861.
Business; Sealing; Shipping; Whaling; Connecticut -- Commerce; Connecticut -- Politics and government -- 1775-1865; Stonington (Conn.); United States -- Politics and government; Merchants; Politicians; Fish, Asa, 1790-1861; Fish, James Deane, b. 1819; Fish, Silas, b. 1825; Perkins, Thomas Clap, 1798-1870
- Inventory
  - Correspondence
    - 1810-1823 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1824-1828 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1829-1830 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1831-1833 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1834-1838 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1839-1843 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1844-1847 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1848 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1849 Feb-Aug (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1849 Sep-Dec (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1850 Jan-Mar (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1850 Apr-Jun (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1850 Jul-Aug (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 1850 Sep-Dec (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1851 Jan-Feb (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 1851 Mar-May (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - 1855 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - n.d. (Box 1, Folder 17)